Register of the Herbert Hoover papers
Hoover Institution Archives
- General Subject File, 1918-1965
  - Conferences
    - Balkans Trade Conference, Geneva, 1947 April (Box-folder 139: 3)
    - European Conference on the Marshall Plan, Paris, 1947 September (Box-folder 139: 4)
    - Council of Foreign Ministers, London, 1947 December (Box-folder 139: 5)
    - Three-Power Conference, London, 1948 February (Box-folder 139: 6)
    - International Trade Organization Conference, Havana, 1948 February-March (Box-folder 139: 7)
    - Four-Power Conference, London, 1948 March (Box-folder 139: 8)
    - Council of Foreign Ministers, Paris, 1949 May-June (Box-folder 139: 9)
  - Cuba, 1960-1961 (Box-folder 140: 1)
    Clippings, radio broadcast transcript, and Congressional Report, Communist Threat to the United States through the Caribbean.
  - Czechoslovakia, clippings and printed article, 1946-1949 (Box-folder 140: 2)
  - Democracy, clippings, 1938-1954 (Box-folder 140: 3)
  - Economic growth, booklet by W. W. Rostow, The Stages of Economic Growth: A Non-Communist Manifesto, 1960 (Box-folder 140: 4)
  - Economic reconversion, clippings, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 140: 5)
  - Education and technology, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 140: 6)
    Conference programs, printed articles, and pamphlets. Includes The Pursuit of Excellence: Education and the Future of America.
  - Eisenhower, Dwight D.
    - General, 1952-1959 (Box-folder 140: 7)
      Typed excerpts from printed sources, press releases, and Eisenhower administration printed reports.
    - Clippings, printed articles, and printed speeches, 1952-1961 (Box-folder 140: 8-9)
    - Clippings, printed articles, and printed speeches (contd.), 1952-1961 (Box-folder 141: 1-6)
  - Europe, clippings and report by Ernest T. Weir, 1946-1954 (Box-folder 142: 1)
  - Finland, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 142: 2)
    Memorandum, press release, clippings, and printed article.
  - Food supply and food relief, 1947-1961 (Box-folder 142: 3)
    Memoranda, statistics, reports, printed articles, and clippings.
  - Foreign aid, 1947-1961 (Box-folder 142: 4)
    Reports, speeches, clippings, and pamphlets. Includes Foreign Aid and You; United States Aid and Indian Economic Development; Voluntary Foreign Aid.
  - Forrestal, James, 1944-1949 (Box-folder 142: 5)
    Speeches, clippings, printed article, and radio broadcast transcript.
  - France, clippings and printed articles, 1945-1949 (Box-folder 142: 6-7)
  - Germany
    - General, 1947-1961 (Box-folder 143: 1)
      Memoranda, letters, reports, bulletins, press releases, circulated documents, printed articles, and clippings. Includes reports by Christopher Emmet and Louis Lochner; The Efforts Made by the Federal Republic to Re-establish the Unity of Germany by Means of All-German Elections; U.S. Department of State bulletin Berlin, 1961.
    - Letters from Germans to Hoover with printed enclosures, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 143: 2-4)
      Letters of gratitude for Hoover's efforts to prevent industrial dismantling of Germany
    - Clippings, 1946-1952 (Box-folder 143: 5)
  - Goebbels, Joseph, diaries
    Material relating to acquisition of Goebbels diaries by the Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace.
    - Memoranda, 1948 (Box-folder 144: 1)
      Memorandum by Hoover with attachments; memoranda by Perrin C. Galpin, Harold H. Fisher, and Frank E. Mason
    - Notes, 1947-1950 (Box-folder 144: 2)
    - Correspondence, 1948 (Box-folder 144: 3-4)
      Includes letters by Hoover and by Norman Armour, Harold I. Baynton, David L. Bazelon, Lucius D. Clay, Harold H. Fisher, Perrin C. Galpin, Hugh Gibson, William F. Heimlich, Richard C. Hunt, Louis Lochner, Kenneth C. Royall, and Lewis L. Strauss
    - Clippings and printed articles, 1948 (Box-folder 144: 5)
  - Great Britain, 1938-1952 (Box-folder 145: 1-2)
    Clippings, printed articles, and pamphlets. Includes Britain's Economic Crisis; Communist Attach on Great Britain.
  - Greece, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 145: 3-4)
    Clippings, printed articles, and pamphlet Devastation in Greece.
  - Guatemala, clippings and report, 1953 (Box-folder 145: 5)
  - Human Events, serial issues, 1962-1964 (Box-folder 145: 6)
  - Hungary, 1946-1951 (Box-folder 146: 1-2)
    Clippings, printed articles, and press release.
  - Ideas and ideology, 1953-1958 (Box-folder 146: 3)
    Clippings, serial issue, and pamphlets. Includes The Gentleman of Culture; The Influence of History; Quest for Freedom; Why Liberty?
  - Intelligence Digest, serial issues, 1951-1953 (Box-folder 146: 4-5)
  - Japan
    - General, 1945-1960 (Box-folder 146: 6)
      Notes, reports by Eugene Dooman and Teigi Tomatsu, and pamphlets. Includes Japan Now; Literature on Contemporary Japan.
    - Clippings and printed articles, 1945-1949 (Box-folder 147: 1-2)
    - Food supply and food relief, letter by Douglas MacArthur and reports, 1945-1948 (Box-folder 147: 3)
    - Reparations
      - General, 1945-1950
        Letters by Hoover and others, memoranda, reports, and clippings. Includes "Report on the Industrial Disarmament of Japan" by the Engineers Joint Council, studies by the Supreme Commander of the Allied Powers staff, and memorandum by Japanese officials.
      - "Report on Industrial Reparations Survey of Japan to the United States of America" by Overseas Consultants, Inc., 1948 (Box-folder 147: 5)
  - Jenner, William E., press releases from the office of Senator Jenner, 1954-1957 (Box-folder 148: 1-2)
  - Kahn, Albert E. (Box-folder 148: 3)
    Correspondence, memoranda, and notes, 1946, re allegations by Kahn in his book The Great Conspiracy of political manipulation of food relief in Russia by the American Relief Administration. Includes letters by Hoover and John Richardson, and memoranda from both sides re potential legal action.
  - Kennedy, John F.--Assassination, clippings, 1963-1964 (Box-folder 148: 4)
  - Korea and Korean War
    - General, 1947-1962 (Box-folder 148: 5)
      Letters, memoranda, notes, press releases, and reports. Includes U.S. War Department report on Korean coal situation, 1947, and report of American-Korean Foundation mission to Korea, 1953.
    - Clippings, printed articles, and Congressional Record excerpts, 1946-1953 (Box-folder 149: 1-2)
  - Labor--United States, 1946-1960 (Box-folder 149: 3)
    Clippings, printed article, and brochure.
  - Latin America, clippings, 1946-1954 (Box-folder 149: 4)
  - Legislation-United States (Box-folder 149: 5)
    Congressional statutes, bills, and resolutions, with associated memoranda and printed articles, 1919-1921, relating to post-World War I economic reconversion and social and welfare measures.
  - Lithuania, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 149: 6)
    Bulletins, notes, and printed excerpts.
  - MacArthur, Douglas, 1951-1955 (Box-folder 149: 7)
    Clippings, pamphlet, and congressional reports. Includes War, Religion, World Peace by MacArthur, and Congressional reports re dismissal of MacArthur.
  - Marshall, George C., 1945-1959 (Box-folder 150: 1-2)
    Memorandum, clippings, and printed articles.
  - Marshall Plan
    - Drafts of writings, memoranda, and notes, 1947-1949 (Box-folder 150: 3)
    - Congressional testimony, briefs, and reports, 1947-1948 (Box-folder 150: 4-5)
      Includes statements by Lewis H. Brown, John J. McCloy, and Ernest T. Weir
    - Clippings, printed articles, and Congressional Record excerpts, 1947-1951 (Box-folder 150: 6)
  - Mills College serial issue, 1960 (Box-folder 150: 7)
  - National Academy of Sciences (Box-folder 151: 1)
    Notes, memoranda, reports, and excerpts from minutes, 1924-1955, relating to Hoover's service as a trustee of the Academy's National Research Fund. Includes resolutions of appreciation.
  - Nuclear weapons and nuclear energy
    - General, 1945-1960 (Box-folder 151: 2)
      Speeches, pamphlets, and Congressional Reports. Includes speech by Vannevar Bush, and printed copy of Modern Man Is Obsolete by Norman Cousins, inscribed to Hoover.
    - United Nations Atomic Energy Commission issuances
      - General reports and memoranda, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 151: 3)
      - Scientific Information Transmitted to the United Nations Atomic Energy Commission by the United States Member, 1946 (Box-folder 151: 4)
        Report series prepared by the office of Bernard M. Baruch.
    - United States Department of State reports, 1946 (Box-folder 151: 5)
      Includes A Report on the International Control of Atomic Energy; United States Atomic Energy Proposals.
    - Clippings and printed articles
      - 1945 (Box-folder 151: 6)
      - 1945 (contd.) (Box-folder 152: 1-2)
      - 1946 (Box-folder 152: 3-5)
      - 1947-1963 (Box-folder 153: 1)
  - Nuremberg War Crime Trials--Ernst von Weizsäcker defense exhibits, 1947-1948
    - Document Book 2: "Weizsäcker's Motives to Stay in Office" (Box-folder 153: 2)
    - Document Book 4: "Struggle at the Side of the Evangelical Church and International Charitable Organizations" (Box-folder 153: 3)
    - Document Book 5: "Assistance to the Persecuted Church" (Box-folder 153: 4)
    - Document Book 6: "Help to the Persecuted" (Box-folder 153: 5)
  - Poland
    - General, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 154: 1)
      Drafts of writings, speech, and pamphlets. Includes Poland: The Children Cannot Wait; Who's Who of the Regime in Poland.
    - Clippings and printed articles
      - 1946 (Box-folder 154: 2-3)
      - 1947 (Box-folder 154: 4)
      - 1948-1961 (Box-folder 154: 5)
  - Presidents--United States (comparative), clippings and charts, 1954-1960 (Box-folder 154: 6)
  - Romania, notes and clippings, 1946-1947 (Box-folder 154: 7)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D.
    - General, 1932-1947 (Box-folder 155: 1)
      Brochure, notes, memorandum, and typed excerpts from printed sources. Includes memorandum and transcript of Congressional hearing re papers of Roosevelt and Roosevelt Presidential Library.
    - Clippings, printed articles, and pamphlet, The Roosevelt Death: A Super Mystery, 1932-1960 (Box-folder 155: 2-3)
  - Social Security System memoranda and congressional testimony, 1949 (Box-folder 155: 4)
  - Sorge, Richard, spy ring, 1949-1951 (Box-folder 155: 5)
    Letter by Hoover, memoranda, investigative certifications, and Congressional Record speeches.
  - Soviet Union
    - Drafts of writings, letters, memoranda, and typed excerpts from printed sources, 1931-1959 (Box-folder 155: 6)
    - Quotations from Soviet leaders with accompanying notes and memoranda, 1918-1964 (Box-folder 155: 7)
    - Diplomatic recognition by United States, 1921-1960 (Box-folder 155: 8)
    - Speeches and radio broadcast transcripts, 1934-1960 (Box-folder 156: 1)
      Includes speeches by Rexford Tugwell and Henry A. Wallace.
    - Congressional Reports, 1957-1963 (Box-folder 156: 2)
    - Pamphlets, 1938-1960 (Box-folder 156: 3)
      Includes Economic Comparisons, USA/USSR; An Investment Banker Visits Russia; Litvinoff; The Nature of the Enemy; The Public Finance of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics; Steel in the Soviet Union; The Unrelenting War
    - Serial issues, 1940-1961 (Box-folder 156: 4)
    - Clippings and printed articles
      - 1946 (Box-folder 156: 5-6)
      - 1946 (contd.) (Box-folder 157: 1)
      - 1947 (Box-folder 157: 2-3)
      - 1948-1949 (Box-folder 157: 4)
      - 1951-1964 (Box-folder 157: 5)
  - Stanford University, 1941-1961 (Box-folder 157: 6)
    Programs, brochure, and serial issue.
  - Stevenson, Adlai E., clippings and printed speeches, 1953-1960 (Box-folder 157: 7)
  - Taiwan
    - Memoranda and notes, 1949-1950 (Box-folder 157: 8)
    - Clippings and Congressional Record excerpts
      - 1946-1949 (Box-folder 157: 9)
      - 1950 (Box-folder 158: 1-3)
      - 1951-1962 (Box-folder 158: 4)
  - Truman, Harry S., 1950-1958 (Box-folder 158: 5)
    Printed speeches, press releases, clippings, and Congressional Record excerpts.
  - United Nations, clippings, 1951-1961 (Box-folder 158: 6)
  - United States
    - Armed Forces
      - Reorganization, 1945-1948 (Box-folder 158: 7)
        Press release and Congressional Report, Unification of the War and Navy Departments and Postwar Organization for National Security.
      - B-36 bomber hearings, 1949 (Box-folder 158: 8)
        Testimony of senior military officers before House Armed Services Committee.
      - B-36 bomber hearings (contd.), 1949 (Box-folder 159: 1-2)
    - Economy
      - Letters, speeches, press releases, and statements, 1950-1960 (Box-folder 159: 3)
        Includes letter by Robert A. Taft, speech by Arthur Kemp, and "Inflation" by Gottfried Haberler
      - Printed matter, 1949-1962 (Box-folder 159: 4-5)
    - Foreign policy
      - Drafts of writings on the Cold War (Box-folder 159: 6)
      - Letters from members of the public in support of Hoover's foreign policy radio broadcast of 1950 December 20, 1950-1951 (Box-folder 160: 1)
      - Statements and radio broadcasts by others, 1958-1961 (Box-folder 160: 2)
      - Printed matter, 1953-1965 (Box-folder 160: 3)
        Includes Survival by Bonner Fellers
    - Politics
      - General, 1954-1962 (Box-folder 160: 4)
        Clippings, printed articles, pamphlets, and press releases. Includes As Seen from the Right by Don Lohbeck.
      - Polling data, 1944-1946 (Box-folder 160: 5)
  - United States Commission on Organization of the Executive Branch of the Government, 1953-1961 (Box-folder 160: 6)
    Letters, clippings, Congressional Record excerpts, and resolutions of appreciation for Hoover's chairmanship.
  - United States Supreme Court, 1958-1959 (Box-folder 160: 7)
    Letter, clippings, printed articles, and pamphlets.
  - Yugoslavia
    - General, 1945-1958 (Box-folder 161: 1)
      Memoranda, report, serial issue, and pamphlets.
    - Clippings and printed articles
      - 1946 (Box-folder 161: 2-4)
      - 1947-1949 (Box-folder 161: 5)
  - Miscellany, 1951-1962 (Box-folder 161: 6)
    Telephone call list, list of World War I relief aides, "Think of a Man" Saturday Review reprint, and printed miscellany.
  - Biographical miscellany, 1939-1963 (Box-folder 161: 7)
    Clippings and other printed references to Hoover. Includes pamphlet by William Starr Myers, The True Republican Record, 1929-1933.
- Financial Records, 1954-1958
  Waldorf-Astoria Hotel room service and long distance telephone service bills
  - 1954
    - January (Box-folder 162: 1)
    - February (Box-folder 162: 2)
    - March (Box-folder 162: 3)
    - April (Box-folder 162: 4)
    - May (Box-folder 162: 5)
    - June (Box-folder 163: 1)
    - July (Box-folder 163: 2)
    - August (Box-folder 163: 3)
    - September (Box-folder 163: 4)
    - October (Box-folder 163: 5)
    - November (Box-folder 164: 1)
    - December (Box-folder 164: 2)
  - 1955
    - January (Box-folder 164: 3)
    - February (Box-folder 164: 4)
    - March (Box-folder 164: 5)
    - April (Box-folder 164: 6)
    - May (Box-folder 164: 7)
    - June (Box-folder 165: 1)
    - July (Box-folder 165: 2)
    - August (Box-folder 165: 3)
    - September (Box-folder 165: 4)
    - October (Box-folder 165: 5)
    - November (Box-folder 165: 6)
    - December (Box-folder 166: 1)
  - 1956
    - January (Box-folder 166: 2)
    - February (Box-folder 166: 3)
    - March (Box-folder 166: 4)
    - April (Box-folder 167: 1)
    - October (Box-folder 167: 2)
    - November (Box-folder 167: 3)
    - December (Box-folder 168: 1)
  - 1957
    - January (Box-folder 168: 2)
    - February (Box-folder 168: 3)
    - March (Box-folder 168: 4)
    - April (Box-folder 169: 1)
    - May (Box-folder 169: 2)
    - June (Box-folder 169: 3)
    - August (Box-folder 169: 4)
    - September (Box-folder 169: 5)
    - October (Box-folder 170: 1)
    - November (Box-folder 170: 2)
    - December (Box-folder 170: 3)
  - 1958
    - January (Box-folder 170: 4)
    - February (Box-folder 171: 1)
    - March (Box-folder 171: 2)
    - April (Box-folder 171: 3)
- Oversize File, 1961-1963 (Box 172)
  Serial issues, mainly of Life and Look, with special articles, mainly relating to communism and the Russian Revolution
- Sound recording of radio news broadcast re Russian trawler, 1960 (Box 173)
- Microfilm of a segment from "Freedom Betrayed," Z edition, Section I, 1963 (Box 173)
- Incremental Materials - not yet described (Box 174)
- Declassified U.S. government records
  - 2015 May release of records, 1939-1953 (Box-folder 175: 1-5)